Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): We all have a collective interest in Americans seeing that we act with integrity and there is no way if you have a huge portfolio concentrated in a particular area or you have a specific stock that would be affected by legislation, there isn't a voice in your head recognizing that and perhaps exercising some influence.
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): over how you might act. If you have a huge renewable energy portfolio then maybe tax credits for renewable energy pass into your mind is, hmm, pretty good idea for my investments. If you have a huge inventory of bank stocks or maybe you have fossil stocks or who knows what. That should never be a voice that influences us. This straightforward amendment for ourselves
and
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): and our spouses is in the interest of this Senate serving the American people. We are at a time when the public opinion of the work we do in Congress is incredibly
low. And
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): every few months, there is an article, I saw one just this last week, about stock trades that occurred before an important public action was taken. And the public goes, there are
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): There it goes again. Why can't they serve the public? I do recognize that this is not legislation that will affect the House. But I was thinking back to when I became Speaker of the House in Oregon. And in our rules, we adopted gift
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): rules that affected only the House of Representatives in Oregon. We called it the $10 standard. You could give someone an apple pie, a cup of coffee, a t-shirt, a ball cap, but you couldn't take a loveliest, couldn't take a person on trips, they couldn't take them to concerts or playoffs or so on and so forth. And it really changed the culture and it led to the Oregon Legislature adopting a very similar law. So I think it's well worth our doing this here
for
Speaker 1 (lower-pitched voice): our Senate. We've been debating this for over a decade. It's been well over a decade when I first became involved in this, and I so appreciate my colleague from Georgia picking up the torch this year and really helping to drive this forward. Let's debate this. Let's vote on this. Let's not table this.